flatmates.com.au 2019-10-19

# Flatmates.com.au - Privacy Policy | Flatmates.com.au

Flatmates.com.au Pty Ltd (Flatmates.com.au) is committed to protecting your privacy. Flatmates.com.au’s privacy policy is outlined below. This privacy policy is regularly reviewed and Flatmates.com.au may amend it from time to time. While Flatmates.com.au will endeavour to notify you of any major changes to this Privacy Policy from time to time, you agree that you will periodically review the most up-to-date version of this Privacy Policy available.

This policy sets out how Flatmates.com.au will collect, use, store, disclose and provide access to information about you and how you can keep that information accurate. By using the Website, you agree to be bound by and consent to this policy.

In this Policy, defined terms have the meaning given to them in Flatmates.com.au’s Terms and Conditions of Use: [flatmates.com.au/terms](https://info.flatmates.com.au/terms).

### 1\. Collection

Flatmates.com.au needs to collect personal information about you primarily to provide you with the Services, with access to the Website, and with other services related to its business. This personal information may include, but is not limited to, your name, telephone number, street address, email address and credit card details.

### 2\. Use and disclosure

**a.** In addition to the primary purpose for which Flatmates.com.au collects and uses your personal information, Flatmates.com.au and its nominated agents may also use the personal information Flatmates.com.au collects, and you consent to Flatmates.com.au’s use of that personal information:

**i.** for purposes necessary or incidental to the provision of goods and services to you including, without limitation, for marketing or promotional purposes;

**ii.** to manage and enhance the Services;

**iii.** to communicate with you, including by email, mail or telephone;

**iv.** to verify your identity;

**v.** to investigate you and your use of the Website and the Services if Flatmates.com.au has reason to suspect that you are in breach of these [Terms and Conditions of Use](https://info.flatmates.com.au/terms) of or have otherwise engaged in unlawful activity; and/or

**vi.** as required or permitted by any law.

**b.** Flatmates.com.au may disclose your personal information, and you consent to Flatmates.com.au disclosing your personal information, to Flatmates.com.au’s related bodies corporate and associated entities (as those terms are defined in the Corporations Act 2001 (Cth)) (Other Entities) whereby your personal information will be collected, used, disclosed, managed and stored in accordance with this policy.

**c.** Flatmates.com.au may also disclose personal information, and you consent to Flatmates.com.au disclosing your personal information, to third parties:

**i.** Flatmates.com.au engages to perform functions or provide goods or services on its behalf;

**ii.** that are Flatmates.com.au’s agents, business partners or joint venture entities;

**iii.** authorised by you to receive information held by Flatmates.com.au;

**iv.** as part of any investigation into you, your activities or the activities of another member, for example, if Flatmates.com.au has reason to suspect that you have committed a breach of these Terms and Conditions of Use or have otherwise engaged in unlawful activity, and Flatmates.com.au reasonably believes that disclosure is necessary to police, any relevant authority or enforcement body, or your internet service provider or network administrator;

**v.** as part of a sale (or proposed sale) of all or part of Flatmates.com.au’s business or the preparation for a listing of Flatmates.com.au; and/or

**vi.** as required or permitted by any law.

**d.** Users of the Website other than yourself cannot access your personal information, such as your address, email address or telephone number, unless you give them access to that information.

**e.** Flatmates.com.au will not disclose to any user other than the intended recipient the contents of any messages sent through the messaging service available on the Website.

**f.** Flatmates.com.au will not disclose to any user the content or source of any complaint made against, or feedback received, about that user (or any other user), including the nature, substance, or origin of that complaint or feedback.

### 3\. Storage

Flatmates.com.au will take all reasonable steps to protect the personal information it holds about you from misuse, loss, or unauthorised access. You acknowledge that the security of online transactions you conduct using this website cannot be guaranteed. Flatmates.com.au does not accept responsibility for misuse of, or loss of, or unauthorised access to, your personal information where the security of that information is not within Flatmates.com.au’s control.

### 4\. Overseas disclosure

**a.** In some circumstances, Flatmates.com.au may need to disclose your personal information to entities located overseas where Flatmates.com.au may not be in a position to know that those entities comply with Australian privacy laws or that the laws of the country in which that entity operates (if any) are substantially similar to Australian privacy laws. When necessary, Flatmates.com.au will inform you that such disclosure may be necessary and will seek your express consent to disclose your personal information to such overseas entities.

**b.** If you request Upgraded Services from Flatmates.com.au, it will be necessary for Flatmates.com.au to collect your credit card details and disclose those details to Stripe or Braintree who may or may not be obliged to comply with the Australian Privacy Principles under the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth). By requesting Upgraded Services, you hereby acknowledge and accept these matters and expressly consent to Flatmates.com.au disclosing your personal information to Stripe or Braintree (wherever located) with full knowledge that it may not be obliged to comply with the Australian Privacy Principles. Flatmates.com.au will not be accountable to you in respect of the use or disclosure by that overseas entity of your personal information and you will not be able to seek redress under the Privacy Act in respect of such use or disclosure. You also expressly acknowledge and accept that you may not be able to seek redress under the laws of the country in which Stripe or Braintree is located or in the country or place in which that personal information is subsequently or otherwise disclosed or accessed. You may withdraw your consent to such disclosure at any time by providing not less than 7 days’ prior written notice to Flatmates.com.au using the contact details provided below. If you do not consent to such disclosure, or you do consent but later withdraw that consent, you will not be able to use the Upgraded Services or, if you have already started using the Upgraded Services at the time you withdraw your consent, you will not be able to continue to use those Upgraded Services. You acknowledge and agree that you will not be entitled to any refund in respect of the Upgraded Services if you withdraw your consent.

### 5\. Cookies

Flatmates.com.au may use cookies on the Website to provide you with a better experience and so that it can gather statistical information about user visits to the website. Cookies are small data files that are downloaded onto your computer when you visit a particular website. Cookies help provide added functionality to the Website or help Flatmates.com.au analyse Website usage. You can disable cookies by turning them off in your browser, however, some areas of the website may not function properly if you do so.

### 6\. Access

You have the right to seek access to and update the personal information which Flatmates.com.au holds about you. You can seek access to and update your personal information by contacting Flatmates.com.au directly at support@flatmates.com.au.

### 7\. Website tracking

Flatmates.com.au (including its related bodies corporate) collects data about your browsing activity on the Website, such as the search terms you have used and other details of the way you use the Website, in order to provide suggested search results to you and, once aggregated with other users’ data, other users based on your and other users’ searches on the Website. This data does not include your personal information. However, this data may be associated with your personal information if you have an Account or if you sign-up for an Account in the future. The collection, use and disclosure, storage of, and access to, that data (if it is associated with your personal information) will be in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Flatmates.com.au will not provide that data to any third parties in a way which will enable them to personally identify you.

### 8\. Subscriptions

If you wish to stop receiving emails or other communications from Flatmates.com.au which may be sent to you in the future, please notify Flatmates.com.au by using the contact details given below, or by clicking the unsubscribe link at the bottom of any email newsletter you have received from Flatmates.com.au.

### 9\. Contact Details

**Flatmates.com.au Team**  
support@flatmates.com.au
